JOSH MAGNESS

Chief Digital Officer

	443.619.0627
	magnessjo@gmail.com
•••	https://joshmagness.com

SKILLS

- Leadership
- Culture Constructor
- Problem Solver
- Macro Strategist
- Communicator
- Mentor
- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- React
- NodeJS
- Scala
- PHP
- Ruby
- GraphQL
- Adobe
- Sketch/Figma
- Storybook
- Styled Components
- CraftCMS
- Drupal
- Test Driven Development
- Linux
- Docker
- Agile
- Jira

PROFILE

I am a human-centric leader with proven success as an executive, manager, and software engineer. As an executive director, I have emphasized a culture of accountability where individuals of all levels are empowered to be successful. My teams comprise engineers, UX/UI designers, information architects, quality assurance specialists, project managers, and coordinators.

As a software engineer, I have contributed to e-commerce systems for Under Armour and &Pizza. In addition, I have created content management systems, APIs, iOS apps, promotion microsites, gaming contests, and kiosk technology solutions. I am an award-winning front-end developer with ten years of server-side experience, including a post-baccalaureate certificate in database management.

WORK EXPERIENCE

The University of Maryland

College Park

The University of Maryland is one of the nation's preeminent higher educational institutions. Their research program ranks among the highest institutions in the world, and the computer science program is steadily rising to one of the nation's finest. The University's tech stack differs per unit, but our default stack is PHP and Javascript.

Chief Digital Officer

October 2021 - Present

Executive Director

I am responsible for the University's digital roadmap. The roadmap is a two-year scoping document with a five-year vision. Major initiatives for the next year include:

- Creating new web applications for umd.edu and admissions.
- Creating the first UMD design system.
- Fearlessly Forward digital campaign.
- Integrating APIs for campus calendars and news feeds throughout the University.

EDUCATION

Masters of Science

Applied Information Technology Towson University

Bachelors of Science

Sports Management
Towson University

SOCIAL



GitHub

https://github.com/magnessjo



Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/magnessjo



Twitter

https://twitter.com/magnessjo

WORK EXPERIENCE - UMD CONTINUED

- Cultivated a culture of accountability through quarterly team objectives for management and individuals.
- Manage the project lifecycle for all new digital properties.
- Direct and track measures of success for the engineering team. Measurements include:
 - Uptime of 99.98%
 - · Page loading performance testing and optimization.
 - · Database query performance and optimization.
 - · Server security (pin) and performance (load) testing.
 - · Bug tracking.
 - · Peer code reviews.
 - 508 compliance reviews.
- Manage the design system and coordinate digital brand requirements with campus partners and vendors.
- Conduct analytics audits for digital campaigns.
- Coordinate with project managers for scoping, requirements, and budgeting. Conducted weekly sprint meetings for all team members.
- Ambassador for engineering best practices for all colleges and schools, and campus offices.
- Facilitate vendor contracts and scopes of work.
- Coordinated the release of digital projects with multiple teams, vendors, and stakeholders.

Director Front-End Development

July 2020 - October 2021

- Led the accessibility compliance initiative with processes for automated reviews, training, and development updates.
- Led the engineering team with multiple successful project launches. Projects include:
 - Web applications for aggregating University news and policies.
 - · Web components for uniformed digital presence.
 - · Digital campaigns such as fearless ideas and quantum.
- Led workshops for best practices in front-end code patterns, user-centric design, and accessibility compliance.
- Created accessibility standards for campus partners and third-party vendors.
- Coordinated with vendors for project requirements and deliverables.

AWARDS

ADDY: SILVER

Baltimore Heritage 2018

ADDY: SILVER

World Heritage USA 2018

ADDY: SILVER

Shenandoah National Park 2018

ADDY: GOLD

HMSHost 2016

ADDY: SILVER

EXIM 2015

ADDY: GOLD

98Online 2014

ADDY: GOLD

Captain John Smith 2013

ADDY: GOLD

Chesapeake Explorer 2012

ADDY: SILVER

Park Points 2011

WORK EXPERIENCE

Under Armour

Baltimore

Under Armour is a world-renowned sports apparel company.

UA has been evolving the sports apparel market for over 20 years through innovation. Under Armour's tech stack includes Javascript, Scala, and NodeJs.

Software Engineer

July 2019 - June 2020

I primarily work on the B2B E-Commerce application called ArmourHouse. ArmourHouse processes over a billion dollars in sales annually. I work on a multidisciplinary team in an agile environment with continuous integration and deployment.

- Led a project to create a design-build system using styled components, typescript, and storybook.
- Led development effort to convert components to be 508 compliant.
- Worked on a large-scale E-Commerce application with a 99.9% uptime using React, Redux, React Router, Apollo, and GraphQL.
- Created API GraphQL endpoints in Scala and PostgreSQL.
- Performed developer code reviews and pull requests.

HAPPY COG

New York (Remote)

Happy Cog is a prominent digital agency in New York. They provide a full range of web services, including design, development, and marketing.

Developer, UX Designer

February 2019 - July 2019

I was a development lead and UX designer for a React web application for a USA Today subsidiary. In addition, I was a member of the &Pizza development team building scalable Angular components for E-commerce and marketing web applications.

• Led development for headless web applications built with React, React Router, and Redux. The single-page applications were WCAG-compliant interfaces pulling data from backends built in PHP and Python.

INTERESTS

Web Components WCAG UX AX **W3C Standards** Soccer Puzzles CrossFit AR Photography Football NASA Animal Rescue Linux Remix JS Problem Solving Design Systems Movies Home Improvement Bulldogs Kayaking Foodie

WORK EXPERIENCE - HC CONTINUED

- Led design workshops for best practices in usability, accessibility, and semantic HTML.
- Deployed Angular components to &Pizza using continuous integration and deployment strategize built into GitHub.
- Mocked multiple client interfaces for A/B usability reviews with custom elements for rapid prototyping.

ALEXANDER TOM INC

Baltimore

Alex+Tom is an award-winning digital agency in the Baltimore area. Alex+Tom provides various services, including design, development, usability testing, and marketing. Alex+Tom was founded over twenty-five years ago and has been a leading usability agency for the last fifteen years.

Tech Lead

November 2011 - March 2019

I was a development lead and UX designer for clients, including the Department of Treasury and the National Park Service. I created award-winning interfaces and web services for government agencies and corporate companies.

- Supervised a full-stack development team with onboarding, code reviews, and project coordination.
- Created over fifteen award-winning user interfaces using vanilla Javascript, React, Ember, and Angular.
- Created server-side web services using Ruby, PHP, and Node. These web services were created in REST or GraphQL using the MVC architectural pattern.
- Mentored stakeholders, designers, content managers, and other developers in creating user-driven and accessible interfaces.
- Utilized an agile development approach to iterate interactive usability and eye-tracking tests. Rapid prototyping daily based on user feedback for comparative analysis.
- Configured and maintained Linux servers for production sites on Amazon EC2. Used Linux distros CentOS, RedHat, and Amazon Linux AMI FedRAMP-certified servers.